<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Error State Kalman Filter on Welcome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/error-state-kalman-filter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Error State Kalman Filter on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/error-state-kalman-filter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Error state Kalman Filter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-8-2-eskf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-8-2-eskf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Error state is the difference between True state $x_t$ and Nominal state $x$. The nominal state does not take into account the noise, just derived from motion equations. As a result there will be accumulate errors, which are collected in the error-state $\delta x$ and the ESKF will estimate these errors. In parallel with integration of the nominal state, the ESKF predicts a Gaussian estimate of the error-state, and inject the mean of error state back to nominal-state. &lt;br&gt;When the IMU measurement data arrives, we integrate it and put it into the nominal state variable. Since this approach does not consider noise, the result will naturally drift quickly, so we hope to put the error part as an error variable in ESKF. ESKF will consider the effects of various noises and zero offsets, and give a Gaussian distribution description of the error state. At the same time, ESKF itself, as a Kalman filter, also has a prediction process and a correction process, and the correction process needs to rely on sensor observations other than the IMU. After the correction, ESKF can give the posterior error Gaussian distribution, and then we can put this part of the error into the nominal state variable, and set ESKF to zero, thus completing a loop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
